Harsh Darji

harshdarji82@gmail.com | 519-702-3060

GitHub | LinkedIn

More than one year of experience as an IT professional focused to obtain a challenging position in an organization that gives me an opportunity for self-improvement and leadership while contributing to the growth of the organization with my technical, innovative, and logical skills.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Programming Languages, Code Structure & Architecture, Front-end & Back-end web development, Self-Starter, Problem Solving, Organizational Skill, Multitasking, Teamwork.

SKILLS

PHP, Java, JavaScript, XML, Swift (iOS), Kotlin (Android), HTML5, CSS, C, C++. **Programming Languages:** React Native, Magento, Laravel, WordPress, jQuery, MVC, MVVM, KnockoutJS. Web Frameworks: Database: MySQL, MySQL Workbench, SQL Lite, SQL, Firebase, Relational Database. Others:

PWA, UI/UX, GIT, Playgrounds, Excel VBA, Ajax, Email Management, API, YAMM,

Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Microsoft Office.

Tools: Visual Studio Code, NetBeans, Jira, Postman, Docker.

EDUCATION

Mobile Application Development (Co-op) | GPA – 3.9

2022 - Present

Fanshawe College, London, ON

Master of Computer Science & Information Technology

July 2018 - Aug 2020

Gujarat University, India

Bachelor of Computer Science & Information Technology

July 2015 - June 2018

Gujarat University, India

EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer | Brainvire | India

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022

- Develop clean and efficient code based on the requirements using various technologies like PHP, Magento, KnockoutJS, MVC, XML, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL Server, etc. Integrate and deploy programs and websites. Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade the existing software. Working in an agile, collaborative environment to build, deploy, configure, and maintain systems.
- Designed, developed, and maintained Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD).
- Responsible for creating and implementing development plans with the help of client communication.

Software Developer Intern | Akash Technolabs Pvt. Ltd | India

Jan 2021 - July 2021

 Developed a web-based application using PHP technologies like Laravel, MVC, SQL server, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS. Also responsible for unit testing, enhancement, and FTP deployment of the application.

PROJECTS

Capstone Project

Virtual Cook | 🔘 | React Native, Material UI, Expo, React-redux, Expo-speech, Expo-sharing, React Native Paper, VS Code

- Followed react redux structure/method. User can get the new recipe notification or can get a random recipe by just shaking the phone. Used Modal to display the recipe filter & sorting options. User to change the language (French/English).
- Implementation of the stack navigation. Two types of the measurements, US system Or Metric. Text to speech feature using expo speech library.
- Moreover, this app has many features like recipe sharing, search option, Dietary restrictions, App color, Random recipe and many more.

Graduate Academic Project

- Developed web application for rental products using on Laravel and followed the MVC/MVVM/MVBC Structure.
- This project offers and individual to rent product(s). For instance, an IT company can rent multiple desks for the employee of the organization.
- · Here, product owners can showcase their product to the renters and also add multiple product images using import file, HTML
- Bootstrap and CSS are used for the UI/Frontend.
- For Database, used MySQL Server and did many things using PHP.
- Admin can manage products & users.
- Used JavaScript and SweetAlert for pop-up messages.
- Country, State and City functionality use Ajax.
- PHP Mailer is used to send conformation mail to the user.

Postgraduate Academic Project

ASK ME For Immigration | () | PHP Core, PHP, MySQL, PHP Mailer, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript

- This project developed using PHP and used MySQL Server to store the data.
- This project provides answers to international students, related to immigration such as students can get details of foreign University(s)/College(s), fees, can mail to the academic advisor or expert, how to apply to that particular institute and many more.
- Here, students can send follow request to the expert and also, they can like the posted question and given replies exactly like the Instagram follow request feature and Facebook post like feature.
- Like Facebook comment section and like button, students can get answer of their question to the comment section and also there is a like button for each question. In addition, there is reply feature for each given answer.
- Notifications, likes on questions & replies, follow request all these features are developed using jQuery, Ajax and JavaScript
- Apart from this, using PHP Mailer, there is a feature for students to send an e-mail to the expert(s).
- Bootstrap and custom CSS used for the User Interface.
- Admin can control all the question(s) & answer(s), expert(s), user(s).

Magento Module

Category Collection Module | () | Magento 2, XML, MVVM, PHP, MySQL, KnockoutJS, CSS, HTML, jQuery, JavaScript

- This module has been built to display the sub category with category banner, at product listing page
- This extension developed using Magento2, PHP and used MySQL Server to store the data.
- Overridden catalog_category_view.xml & product/list using MVVM pattern.
- In the list.phtml file, custom code has been written using PHP core, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, Inline CSS. Created new category attribute to fetch the custom category banner. New attribute created using InstallData and UpgradeData.
- Module enable/disable functionality provided using system.xml
- To fetch data, some custom function has been **created** in **block** and **helper** file (block/Category.php, Helper/Data.php).